Guide to the McKinney Family Papers, 1823-1964
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
McKinney Family Papers
1823-1964
McKinney family
4.6 cubic feet (29 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Papers of the McKinney Family from the McKinney Family Papers. Contains correspondence, notes, clippings, obituaries, business papers and ephemera.
Biographical Note
The three parts of the McKinney Family papers are the Jean Webster Papers, the Samuel Clemens Papers and the McKinney Family Papers. The common thread amongst these groups of materials is Jean Webster. She was the grand niece of Samuel Clemens, and became part of the McKinney Family when she married Glenn Ford McKinney (see the McKinney chart below).
Glenn Ford McKinney was the son of John Luke McKinney (co-founder of Standard Oil) and Ida DeEtte Ford. Ida and John also had a daughter, Ethelyn McKinney, a member of the Smith College Class of 1895.
McKinney Family Genealogy
1770 John McKinney born in Ireland
ca. 1790-1800? John McKinney married Rebecca Arthur
1810 James McKinney (one of John and Rebecca's eight children) born
1837 James McKinney married Lydia Drury Turner
1842 John Luke McKinney (son of James and Lydia) born in Pittsfield, PA
1866 John Luke McKinney married Ida DeEtte Ford (daughter of John C. Ford and Jerusha Jane Dalrymple)
1869 Glenn Ford McKinney born
1871 or 1872 Ida Ethelyn McKinney born
Scope and Content Note
The McKinney Family Papers include correspondence, photographs, legal papers, ephemera and genealogical papers for members of the McKinney and related families. The collection also includes some family photographs, notably of Samuel Langhorne Clemens.
The McKinney Family Papers form only one part of the McKinney Family Papers.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Separated Materials
Materials related to Samuel Clemens and Jean Webster have been separated from this collection and grouped into their respective collections:
Samuel L. Clemens Papers
Jean Webster Papers
Subject Headings
Names:
Webster, Jean, 1876-1916; Twain, Mark, 1835-1910; Connor, Charlotte B.; Ford, Ida DeEtte McKinney; Ford, Jerusha Jane Dalrymple; Ford, John C., 1820-1896; McKinney, Ethelyn; McKinney, George R.; McKinney, Glenn Ford; McKinney, James; McKinney, John, ca. 1770-1840; McKinney, John Luke; Turner, Lydia Drury; Clemens family; Moffett family; Turner family; Webster family
Subjects:
Family--New York (State); Women--Diaries
Document Types:
Photographs; Ephemera; Diaries
VCL Categories:
Family
Note
Forms part of the McKinney Family Papers.
Encoding Information
Finding aid encoded by Jason Kovari, 26 February 2009. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, March 2024.
Acquisition Information
Included in the gift of the Jean Webster McKinney Family Papers, given to the college in 1977 by Jean Connor, Jean Webster's daughter, and her husband, Ralph Connor.
Series List
- Series I. John McKinney, (Box 1)
- Series II. James McKinney and Lydia Drury Turner, (Box 1)
- Series III. John Luke McKinney, (Boxes 2-8)
- Series IV. John C. Ford, (Box 9)
- Series V. Jerusha Jane Dalrymple Ford, (Box 9)
- Series VI. Ida DeEtte Ford McKinney, (Boxes 9-10)
- Series VII. Glenn Ford McKinney, (Boxes 11-13 and 29)
  Subseries A: Glenn Ford McKinney Materials
  Subseries B: Jean Webster to Glenn Ford McKinney Materials
- Series VIII. Ethelyn McKinney, (Boxes 14-22)
- Series IX. Photographs, (Boxes 23-28)
  Subseries A: McKinney Family Photographs
  Subseries B: Clemens Family Photographs
  Subseries C: Moffett Family Photographs
  Subseries D: Webster Family Photographs
- Series X. Ephemera, (Box 28)
Container List
- SERIES I. John McKinney
  - Envelope for Deed, 1823 (Folder 1.1)
  - Joseph W. Douglas Deed to John McKinney, 10 Dec 1823 (Folder 1.2)
  - Copy of John McKinney's Will with note, undated (Folder 1.3)
  - Photo of John McKinney's Memorial, undated (Folder 1.4)
  - Draft of the Biography of John McKinney, undated (Folder 1.5)
  - Biography of John McKinney (p. 1-2), undated (Folder 1.6)
  - Biography of John McKinney (p. 3-4), undated (Folder 1.7)
  - Genealogy of the McKinney Family, undated (Folder 1.8)
  - Marriage Certificate of Squire and Sarah Boone, 23 July 1720 (Folder 1.9)
  - Letter from David L. Clawson to Jean McKinney Connor, 10 Mar 1969 (Folder 1.10)
  - Letter from David L. Clawson to Mrs. Connor re: Boone family tree, 27 Apr 1969 (Folder 1.11)
- SERIES II. James McKinney and Lydia Drury Turner
  - Envelope with info about James McKinney's Army commission, undated (Folder 1.12)
  - Photo of James McKinney, undated (Folder 1.13)
  - Photo of Lydia Drury Turner, 1898 (Folder 1.14)
  - Obituaries of James McKinney and Lydia Drury Turner, undated (Folder 1.15)
  - Clipping re: Mean Township, undated (Folder 1.16)
  - Clipping re: Major James McKinney, undated (Folder 1.17)
  - Clipping re: Luke Turner and the Arthur Family, undated (Folder 1.18)
  - Genealogy of the Descendants of Humphrey Turner. Compiled by Jacob Turner, Esq., 1852 (Folder 1.19)
  - Envelope for notes pertaining to McKinney and Turner Families, undated (Folder 1.20)
  - Notes on McKinney and Turner Families, undated (Folder 1.21)
  - Notes on Turner Family, undated (Folder 1.22)
- SERIES III. John Luke McKinney, 1863-1959
  - Letter from John Luke McKinney to Ida Ford with envelope, undated (Folder 2.1)
  - Letter to Ida from [K.B.R.?], 9 Feb 1863 (Folder 2.1)
  - Letter to Ida from W.V. Ford [Harper's Ferry], 6 Apr 1863 (Folder 2.3)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope, undated (Folder 2.4)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Harrisburg, PA], 4 July 1863 (Folder 2.5)
  - Copy of Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney, 4 July 1863 (Folder 2.6)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope, 4 Sep 1863 (Folder 2.7)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Franklin, PA], Sep 1863 (Folder 2.8)
  - Letter to Ida from W.V. Ford [Beverly, VA], 23 Oct 1863 (Folder 2.9)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Pittsfield, PA], 5 Nov 1863 (Folder 2.10)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ida [Ohio], 22 Nov 1863 (Folder 2.11)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Pittsfield, PA], undated (Folder 2.12)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Pittsfield, PA], 7 Jan 1864 (Folder 2.13)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Pittsfield, PA], 3 Feb 1864 (Folder 2.14)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Oil City, PA], 12 June 1864 (Folder 2.15)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [St. Charles Hotel in Pittsburgh, PA], 8 July 1864 (Folder 2.16)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [St. Charles Hotel in Pittsburgh, PA], 17 July 1864 (Folder 2.17)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney [Oil City, PA], 4 Aug 1864 (Folder 2.18)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Franklin, PA], 15 Aug 1864 (Folder 2.19)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Garry R.R. Office], 7 Sep 1864 (Folder 2.20)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Franklin, PA], 14 Sep 1864 (Folder 2.21)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Franklin, PA], 23 Sep 1864 (Folder 2.22)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Franklin, PA], 14 Nov 1864 (Folder 2.23)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Philadelphia, PA], 13 Dec 1864 (Folder 2.24)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Philadelphia, PA], 1 Jan 1865 (Folder 2.25)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Philadelphia, PA], 22 Jan 1865 (Folder 2.26)
  - Letter to Ida from George McMaster [Meadville, PA], 11 May 1865 (Folder 2.27)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Philadelphia, PA], 13 June 1865 (Folder 2.28)
  - Letter to Ida from "Ham and Eggs" (probably J. L. McKinney) [Petroleum Center], 20-21 June 1865 (Folder 2.29)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Philadelphia, PA], 26 June 1865 (Folder 2.30)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Franklin, PA], 10 Aug 1865 (Folder 2.31)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Petroleum Center], 12 Nov 1865 (Folder 2.32)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope Franklin, PA], 19 Nov 1865 (Folder 2.33)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Philadelphia, PA], 6 Dec 1865 (Folder 2.34)
  - Letter to Ida from Julia [Pittsfield, PA], 17 Dec 1865 (Folder 2.35)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [St. Nicholas Hotel, New York, N.Y.], 17 Dec 1865 (Folder 2.36)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Philadelphia, PA], 24 Dec 1865 (Folder 2.37)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [St. Nicholas Hotel, New York, N.Y.], 5 Jan 1866 (Folder 2.38)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [St.Nicholas Hotel, New York, N.Y.], 10 Jan 1866 (Folder 2.39)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Philadelphia, PA], 14 Jan 1866 (Folder 2.40)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Philadelphia, PA], 27 Jan 1866 (Folder 2.41)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Philadelphia, PA], 5 Feb 1866 (Folder 2.42)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [St.Nicholas Hotel, New York, N.Y.], 9 Feb 1866 (Folder 2.43)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Philadelphia, PA], 15 Feb 1866 (Folder 2.44)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney [New York], 18 Feb 1866 (Folder 2.45)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Pittsfield, PA], 25 Feb 1866 (Folder 2.46)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Pittsfield, PA], 5 Mar 1866 (Folder 2.47)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Pittsfield, PA], 14 Mar 1866 (Folder 2.48)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Pittsfield, PA], 24 Mar 1866 (Folder 2.49)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 29 Mar 1866 (Folder 2.50)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Philadelphia, PA], 4 Apr 1866 (Folder 3.1)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 18 Apr 1866 (Folder 3.2)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 23 Apr 1866 (Folder 3.3)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 27 Apr 1866 (Folder 3.4)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope, 13 May 1866 (Folder 3.5)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Petroleum Center], 15 May 1866 (Folder 3.6)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 1 June 1866 (Folder 3.7)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 8 June 1866 (Folder 3.8)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 14 June 1866 (Folder 3.9)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 17 June 1866 (Folder 3.10)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 21 June 1866 (Folder 3.11)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [McHenry House, Meadville, PA], 3 Aug 1866 (Folder 3.12)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Brandrills House, New York], 28 Oct 1866 (Folder 3.13)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Rochester House, Petroleum Center], 21 Nov 1866 (Folder 3.14)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Franklin, PA], 25 Nov 1866 (Folder 3.15)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 9 Dec 1866 (Folder 3.16)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 13 Dec 1866 (Folder 3.17)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 16 Dec 1866 (Folder 3.18)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 23 Dec 1866 (Folder 3.19)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 26 Dec 1866 (Folder 3.20)
  - Envelope addressed to Mrs. J. L. McKinney of Lilasville Crawford Co., PA, 26 Dec 1886 (Folder 3.21)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 1 Jan 1867 (Folder 3.22)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 6 Jan 1867 (Folder 3.23)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 13 Jan 1867 (Folder 3.24)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 17 Jan 1867 (Folder 3.25)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope [New York], 20 Jan 1867 (Folder 3.26)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney with envelope, 30 Jan 1867 (Folder 3.27)
  - Letter to Ida from J. L. McKinney, 7 Feb 1867 (Folder 3.28)
  - Telegram to J. L. McKinney from James Parshall, undated (Folder 3.29)
  - Poems in J. L. McKinney's handwriting, undated (Folder 3.30)
  - J. L. McKinney's Ledger, 1868 (Folder 3.31)
  - Letter from (J. L. McKinney) to his daughter (Ethelyn) [Titusville, PA], 9 Aug 1886 (Folder 3.32)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 27 Aug 1886 (Folder 3.33)
  - Receipt from R.H. Macy and Co. [New York], 23 June 1890 (Folder 3.34)
  - Letter to [Ethelyn] from [John] [The Jackson Sanatorium, New York], 15 Feb 1892 (Folder 3.35)
  - Letter to "Momma" and Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with clipping re: fire and flood of 1892 in Titusville, PA, 3 Apr 1892; 5 June 1892; undated (Folder 3.36)
  - Clipping re: Oil business in Pennsylvania, 1899 (Folder 3.37)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 21 Dec 1905 (Folder 3.38)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Titusville, PA], 30 Dec 1906 (Folder 3.39)
  - Fragment of letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, Pa], 14 Feb 1907 (Folder 3.40)
  - Letter to (Ethelyn ?) from "Grandmother", 14 Feb 1907 (Folder 3.41)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Titusville, PA], 7 Apr 1907 (Folder 3.42)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney, 15 Apr 1907 (Folder 3.43)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney, 4 May 1907 (Folder 3.44)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Titusville, PA], 10 May 1907 (Folder 3.45)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 24 Oct 1908 (Folder 3.46)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Titusville, PA], 11 Apr 1909 (Folder 3.47)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 9 Nov 1909 (Folder 3.48)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Titusville, PA], 10 Nov 1909 (Folder 3.49)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Hotel Iroquois, Buffalo, NY], 4 Feb 1910 (Folder 3.50)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from his son Glenn Ford McKinney [New York], 24 May 1910 (Folder 3.51)
  - Photo of J. L. McKinney's Residence in Titusville, PA, 12 Feb 1910 (Folder 3.52)
  - Postcard to J. L. McKinney from John R. McKinney, 21 June 1910 (Folder 3.53)
  - Letter to (Ethelyn?) from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 25 Sep 1910 (Folder 3.54)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Titusville, PA], 18 Dec 1910 (Folder 3.55)
  - Letter to (Ethelyn?) from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 26 Dec 1910 (Folder 3.56)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Titusville, PA], 27 Dec 1910 (Folder 3.57)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 2 Jan 1911 (Folder 3.58)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 4 Jan 1911 (Folder 3.59)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 28 Jan 1911 (Folder 3.60)
  - Letter to (Ethelyn?) from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 29 Jan 1911 (Folder 3.61)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Titusville, PA], 2 Feb 1911 (Folder 3.62)
  - Letter to (Ethelyn?) from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 26 Feb 1911 (Folder 3.63)
  - Letter to (Ethelyn ?) from J. L. McKinney [The Madison Square, NY], 26 Sep 1911 (Folder 3.64)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Titusville, PA], 14 Nov 1911 (Folder 3.65)
  - Certificate celebrating the erection of the Lincoln Memorial Hall in Hodgenville, KT by J.K. McKinney, Nov 1911 (Folder 3.66)
  - Letter from J. L. McKinney to is children [Titusville, PA], 25 Dec 1911 (Folder 3.67)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Palace Hotel, Pontresina, Ireland], 11 July 1912 (Folder 4.1)
  - New York Times clipping: "Parties and People", 11 July 1912 (Folder 4.2)
  - 3 clippings re: Commercial Bank of Titusville, Standard Oil of NJ, and J. L. McKinney's health, undated (Folder 4.3)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Pontresina, Ireland], 17 July 1912 (Folder 4.4)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Hotel Des Balances and Bellevue, Lucerne], 21 July 1912 (Folder 4.5)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with photo [Lucerne], 23 July 1912 (Folder 4.6)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Hotel Beau.Rivage.Thun. Schweiz], 29 July 1912 (Folder 4.7)
  - Postcards to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney, 22 July 1912 (Folder 4.8)
  - Postcards to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney, 26 July 1912 (Folder 4.8)
  - Postcards to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney, 1 Aug 1912 (Folder 4.8)
  - Postcards to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney, 4 Aug 1912 (Folder 4.8)
  - Postcards of Meiringen and Geneva (mint condition), undated; (2) (Folder 4.9)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Hotel Du Sauvage, Meiringen], 2 Aug 1912 (Folder 4.10)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Hotel Victoria Et D'Angleterre, Zermott, Switzerland], 6 Aug 1912 (Folder 4.11)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Grands Hotels Manney, Montreux], 8 Aug 1912 (Folder 4.12)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Hotel De Lille And D'Albion, Paris], 12 Aug 1912 (Folder 4.13)
  - Clipping re: Standard Oil Stocks, Aug 1912 (Folder 4.14)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Paris], 16 Aug 1912 (Folder 4.15)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Paris], 18 Aug 1912 (Folder 4.16)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [On board des Dampfers, 24 Aug 1912 (Folder 4.17)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [The Wolcott, New York], 5 Sept 1912 (Folder 4.18)
  - Commercial Bank of Titusville Statement, 2 Nov 1912 (Folder 4.19)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 27 Nov 1912 (Folder 4.20)
  - Stock Report [Pittsburgh, PA], 25 Nov 1912 (Folder 4.21)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 17 Dec 1912 (Folder 4.22)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope, 21 Dec 1912 (Folder 4.23)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Titusville, PA], 24 Dec 1912 (Folder 4.24)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 29 Dec 1912 (Folder 4.25)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 5 Jan 1913 (Folder 4.26)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 10 Jan 1913 (Folder 4.27)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 15 Jan 1913 (Folder 4.28)
  - Letter to Glenn and Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 16 Jan 1913 (Folder 4.29)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Pittsburgh, PA], 21 Jan 1913 (Folder 4.30)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 26 Jan 1913 (Folder 4.31)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 1 Feb 1913 (Folder 4.32)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [The Wolcott, New York], 1 Mar 1913 (Folder 4.33)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 23 Mar 1913 (Folder 4.34)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 28 Mar 1913 (Folder 4.35)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 2 Apr 1913 (Folder 4.36)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from the Petroleum Center [Titusville. PA], 12 Apr 1913 (Folder 4.37)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 14 Apr 1913 (Folder 4.38)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 15 May 1913 (Folder 4.39)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 18 May 1913 (Folder 4.40)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 19 May 1913 (Folder 4.41)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 14 May 1913 (Folder 4.42)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 1 June 1913 (Folder 4.43)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 5 June 1913 (Folder 4.44)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 26 June 1913 (Folder 4.45)
  - Letter from J. L. McKinney to his children (Ethelyn and Glenn) with envelope and stock certificate [Titusville, PA], 29 June 1913 (Folder 4.46)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 3 July 1913 (Folder 4.47)
  - Letter from J. L. McKinney to his children [Titusville, PA], 6 July 1913 (Folder 4.48)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 10 July 1913 (Folder 4.49)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Titusville, PA], 20 July 1913 (Folder 4.50)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Aboard des Dampfers], 25 July 1913 (Folder 4.51)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Paris], 30 July 1913 (Folder 4.52)
  - Postcards to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney, July-Aug 1913 (Folder 4.53)
  - Postcards, 1913 (Folder 4.54)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Karlsbad], 12 Aug 1913 (Folder 4.55)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Karlsbad], 19 Aug 1913 (Folder 4.56)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Baden-Baden], 20 Aug 1913 (Folder 4.57)
  - Letter to Glenn Ford McKinney from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Schwartzwald], 28 Aug 1913 (Folder 4.58)
  - Letter to Glenn Ford McKinney from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Besiter], 30 Aug 1913 (Folder 4.59)
  - Letter to Glenn from J. L. McKinney [Paris], 3 Sept 1913 (Folder 4.60)
  - Letter to [Glenn and Ethelyn?] [Paris], 9 Sept 1913 (Folder 4.61)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Paris], 16 Sept 1913 (Folder 4.62)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Paris], 20 Sept 1913 (Folder 4.63)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney with envelope [Paris], 23 Sept 1913 (Folder 5.1)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 27 Nov 1913 (Folder 5.2)
  - Letter to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn, 30 Nov 1913 (Folder 5.3)
  - 2 Christmas Cards and 1 envelope to J. L. McKinney from Ethelyn and Glenn, 1913 (Folder 5.4)
  - Letter to (Glenn and Ethelyn ?) from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 4 Jan 1914 (Folder 5.5)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 18 Jan 1914 (Folder 5.6)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 27 Feb 1914 (Folder 5.7)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 14 May, 1914 (Folder 5.8)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 24 May 1914 (Folder 5.9)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 21 June 1914 (Folder 5.10)
  - Letter to (Glenn or Ethelyn?) from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 18 Oct 1914 (Folder 5.11)
  - Letter to (Glenn and Ethelyn?) from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 2 Jan 1915 (Folder 5.12)
  - Handsome testimonial presented to J. L. McKinney in honor of his services to the Commercial Bank of Titusville, 12 Jan 1916 (Folder 5.13)
  - Clipping re: presentation of "Handsome Testimonial to Hon. J. L. McKinney", 1916 (Folder 5.14)
  - Letter to [Glenn and Ethelyn?] from J. L. McKinney, 27 Oct 1916 (Folder 5.15)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney, 10 Feb 1917 (Folder 5.16)
  - Clippings: "E.E. Loomis is chosen President of Leigh" and "Timely Marked Topics", 1917; (2) (Folder 5.17)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 22 Feb 1917 (Folder 5.18)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 28 Mar 1917 (Folder 5.19)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney, 1 Apr 1917 (Folder 5.20)
  - Letter to Ethelyn from J. L. McKinney [Titusville, PA], 2 Apr 1917 (Folder 5.21)